themexpert.com 2018-09-03

# Privacy Policy - ThemeXpert

This privacy policy sets out how **ThemeXpert** uses and protects any information that you have given to us when you use this website.

**ThemeXpert** is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

**ThemeXpert** may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

## Information that we collect

We may collect the following information:

  * Name and contact information including email address.
  * Demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests.
  * Other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers.
  * Website URL where our component installed.

## Record of consents and processing activities

We store and track any consent given by you on this website in order to register, create an account, contacting us, requesting for support or sending a promo code request, etc. We keep a consents registry for users that accepted our privacy policy.

We keep a record of processing activities entitled to the owner of this website in order to be compliant with the EU GDPR article (EU) 2016/679

## What we do with the information we gather

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Internal record keeping.
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.

## Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

## How we use cookies and essential cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyze web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

You may choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may stop our website from functioning correctly.

## Essential Cookies

When you access our website, the website will create an essential cookie that is needed for the operation of the website. The essential cookie will remember that you are logged in and that your session is secure.

## 3rd Party Cookies

### Google Analytics

This cookie allows us to see information on user website activities including, but not limited to page views, source and time spent on website. The information is depersonalized and is displayed as numbers, meaning it cannot be tracked back to individuals. This will help to protect your privacy. Using Google Analytics we can see what content is popular on our website, and strive to give you more of the things you enjoy reading and watching.

### Google Adwords

Using Google Adwords code we are able to see which pages helped lead to an action taken by a visitor (conversion). This allows us to make better use of our paid search budget.

### ShareThis

Using ShareThis to render social bookmark buttons in our blog posts. This allows you to be able to quickly share a post on our site to your favorite social media.

## Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## Controlling your personal information

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or you prefer to delete your account, you may do so by heading over to your profile page.
